《絕命律師》前情提要
Previously on AMC's "Better Call Saul"...
你剛剛承認犯了一項重罪你知道吧
You do realize you just confessed to a felony.
就我們倆  空口無憑
It's your word against mine.
如果那盤帶子沒用  還有什么意義
If that tape is useless, what's the point?
-是我干的  -關掉
- It was me. - Turn that off!
絕對不能告訴任何人
You cannot tell anyone.
今天有那么一會兒  查克沒有討厭我
For 10 minutes today, Chuck didn't hate me.
別以為我會忘記今天在這發生的事
Don't think I'll ever forget what happened here today.
你會付出代價的
And you will pay.
校對     喃喃
后期     蠟筆小新的眉毛  8T
總監     喃喃
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯     杏仁斯嘉麗   克里斯   吃冰棒
時間軸     念念   今   壬虛浪影
翻譯     十月   joy_bwl   Eunice
你可以把紅桃五放上去
You can move the red five up.
沒錯
Oh, yeah.
謝謝  先生
Thank you, sir.
這些牌為什么有孔
Why do the cards have holes in them?
這些是賭場淘汰的舊牌
They're, uh -- These are used cards from the casino.
賭場要是想把一副牌換掉
Once the casino pulls a deck of cards out of action,
會在牌上打孔  再把牌賣給公眾
they drill a hole through them and sell 'em to the public.
很便宜  一兩塊
Just a buck or 2.
瞧瞧啊
Look at that.
我想這樣是防止人出老千
I suppose that's to prevent people from cheating with them.
是啊
Yeah.
也算是不錯的紀念品
Makes for a good souvenir.
這些是凱撒賭場的
These are from Caesars.
我沒去過
I've never been.
越來越暗了
Getting dark.
不好意思  好像該關燈了
I hate to say it, but I think it might be time to kill the lights.
是的  先生  沒問題
Oh, yes, sir. Of course.
真不用我給你泡杯茶嗎
You sure I can't make you a cup of tea?
不用了  先生  謝謝
I'm fine, sir. Thank you.
那好吧
All right, then.
絕命律師
第三季 第二集
正是我需要的
Just what I needed.
喝光  伙計們  別睡著了
Drink up, guys. Don't need you fallin' asleep.
電池你解決掉了嗎
Hey, you take care of that battery?
解決了  最后還是沒電了
Oh, yeah. It finally shit the bed,
但我們幾小時之前換掉了
but we swapped it out a couple hours ago.
好  現在怎么樣
Okay. How'd it go?
沒問題
No problem.
-有人看見你嗎  -沒有  一個人都沒有
- Anyone see you? - Nah. Dead over there.
好了
A'ight.
保持清醒
Stay awake.
目標
無信號
死路
洛博羅炸雞店
有人嗎
Hello?
快進來
Come on in.
我是弗朗西斯卡·莉蒂
I'm Francesca Liddy.
我是來面試的
I'm here for the interview.
吉米·麥吉爾
Jimmy McGill.
是你來早了  還是我遲到了
Are you, uh, running early, or am I running late?
抱歉  是我來早了
No, sorry. I'm a little early.
沒關系
It's not a problem.
早點總沒錯
Never bad to be early...
不過死亡或交稅什么的另當別論
except in death and taxes and...some other things.
我能問個問題嗎
Hey, can I ask you a question?
好
Sure.
你覺得這畫得直嗎
Does that look straight to you?
我覺得那邊
I think there -- that -- that side --
有點彎
I think you're a little crooked --
M的下面
the bottom of the "M" there.
是有點彎
Yeah. A little crooked.
你在車管部做了七年之后辭職了
So, you're coming off of seven years at the MVD?
是的
I am, yeah.
問題是  為什么新墨西哥州
Here's a question -- how come New Mexico
不像其他州一樣管它叫車管所呢
doesn't call it the DMV like every other state?
這個問題問得好
Well, that's a great question.
就像在亞利桑那州
Just like in Arizona,
車輛管理部分屬交通運輸部  是一個部門
the Motor Vehicles Division is part of the DOT, a division,
然而其他州大多都是車管所
whereas, in most other states, the DMV,
也就是車輛管理所  自成一體  所以
or Department of Motor Vehicles is its own entity, so...
不知道這個回答你滿不滿意
I don't know if that answers the question,
反正政府就這么叫的
except to say that's the government for you.
你說得對
You got that right.
我才不會叫它車管部呢
Well, I, for one, am not calling it the MVD --
我會一直叫它車管所
DMV all the way.
你覺得在那里工作  最大的收獲是什么
What do you think you learned the most working there?
耐心  交際手腕
Patience, diplomacy.
在那兒會碰到各種各樣的人
you meet a-all sorts of people down there,
大多數都很不錯  非常友善
a-and most are really great, really friendly,
但你會遇到一些愛挑事的人
but you encounter some who are upset, belligerent.
那老年人呢
What about old folks?
你遇到過很多嗎
Uh, you get your fair share of them?
有好多上了年紀的司機
Oh, lots of elderly drivers.
七十五歲之后  他們得再考一次駕照
After 75, they need to take their test again,
要是沒通過
so if they don't pass,
你就得給他們解釋
you have to explain to them
為什么不能幫他們更新駕照
why their license isn't being renewed,
對他們來說挺難接受的
which is hard for them.
那你會怎么說
What do you say then?
你吼過他們嗎
Do you ever... yell at them?
那些老不死的
I mean, geezers, right?
你怎么可能不吼呢
How can you not?
我從來沒有
No, I would never.
沒有
No.
你也不應該  這問題是個陷阱
Nor should you. That was a trick question.
你通過了  很棒
You passed with flying colors -- very good.
好
Okay.
吉米和我的需求差異很大
Well, then, so, Jimmy and I have very different needs.
他的業務大多是幫老年人立遺囑
His practice is mostly wills for senior citizens,
我現在只專心應付一位委托人
while I'm focused on a single client at the moment,
梅薩維德銀行  因為他們的規章制度
Mesa Verde, with banking regulations
所以有成噸的文書工作
that generate a ton of paperwork,
我想找一個
so I'm looking for someone
有條理又注重細節的人
with an eye for organization and detail.
車管所很看重這一點
Well, DMV's great for that --
那些駕照可是有上千處細節
tons of detail in those driver's licenses.
我們確實每天見到上百張面孔
We did see hundreds of people every day,
你可不想把他們的表格弄錯
and you'd never want to let a mistake slip through on their forms.
那樣會引起一大堆問題
You'd just have a horrible cascade of problems.
聽上去很有挑戰性
Sounds challenging.
為什么選擇律所
So, why the law?
為什么離開車管所  車管部
I mean, why leave the DMV -- or MVD?
我覺得
I have to imagine
你們的待遇一定很不錯吧
you'll be giving up a good benefits package.
完備的醫保和退休計劃  但...
Good healthcare and retirement plans, but...
政府工作總牽扯到官僚主義
there's a bureaucracy to government work
最終讓我很沮喪
that ultimately became too frustrating.
用你們的話說就是繁文縟節太多
I guess what you'd call it -- too much red tape.
我想去一個能成就一番事業的地方
I just want to be somewhere I can make a difference.
那就是我們  我們想干出一番事業
Well, that's us. We're all about making a difference.
你的簡歷上還寫到你熟練使用
And I see here both Word and Excel --
-文字和表格辦公軟件  -沒錯
- you're comfortable with? - Absolutely.
辦公文件  天啊
Excel and Word? Wow.
你說到老年人時就已經打動我了
Well, you had me at old people.
我有個問題  你能今天就來上班嗎
Hey, here's a question -- can you start today?
-我...  -那個...
- I, uh... - Can --
可以
Yes?
-太棒了  -你能...
- Fantastic. - Now, can you --
你能等我們商量下嗎  弗朗西斯卡
Can you just give us a second, Francesca?
當然
Absolutely. I...
沒問題
Of course.
謝謝
Thank you.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我喜歡她
What? I like her.
"你能今天就來上班嗎"
"Can you start today?"
你不覺得我們應該先看看別的簡歷嗎
Don't you think we should see some more résumés --
多看幾份
like, a lot more?
她是第一個面試的
She is our first interview.
我們還沒檢查她的推薦信
We haven't even checked her references.
我們這就查
So we'll check 'em.
金  你一直在尋找一位律師助理
Kim, you've been takin' forever searching for a paralegal.
我們需要幫手
We need help here.
我還沒找到合適的
I haven't found the right fit.
因為你總苛求完美
Yeah, 'cause you're searching for perfection,
完美可是尋找夠格人選的頭號障礙
and perfection is the enemy of perfectly adequate.
你的標準就是夠格嗎
Oh, so that's the bar here -- adequate?
她不僅夠格  她在車管所工作過
She's more than adequate! She worked at the DMV.
那可是不折不扣的地獄
That's like the fifth circle of Hell.
她足以勝任了
Look, she's overqualified.
如果實在不行  我們就開除她
I-If it doesn't work out, we can fire her.
沒什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
你不覺得有法律實踐經驗的人
Don't you think someone with some actual legal experience
會更合適嗎
would be better?
電視上該放我的廣告了  還有...
Look, I've got a commercial airing in...
十一分鐘
11 minutes,
電話會沒完沒了響個不停
so the phones are gonna be ringin' off the hook
我需要幫助
and I need help.
我們能先試用一下她嗎
Can we give her a test run, please?
我有不錯的預感
I got a good feeling about this.
拜托了  金
Come on, Kim.
讓這些老年人打電話
Now, getting these oldsters to call --
就已經成功了一半
that's half the battle,
他們需要聽到友好的聲音
so they need to hear a friendly voice.
友好  沒問題
Friendly? Absolutely.
聲音洪亮  發音清晰
Speak loudly and clearly,
但也別太過頭了
but, uh, be careful with the loud and clear,
可能會讓人誤解為生氣
'cause it can come off as angry.
親民點
Be folksy.
聲音中帶點陽光
Put a little sunshine in your voice.
-明白  -好
- Got it. - Okay.
你想喝咖啡或是水嗎
You need coffee or water?
抓緊時間去廁所...
You need to hit the head before things --
開始了
Oh, there it goes.
吉米·麥吉爾辦公室  有什么能幫您的
Offices of Jimmy McGill. How may I help you?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
能稍等一會嗎  謝謝
May I put you on hold? Thank you.
吉米·麥吉爾辦公室
Offices of Jimmy McGill.
請稍候
Please hold.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
我能為您做點什么
What can I do for you?
沒錯
Uh, that's right.
廣告上的那個吉米·麥吉爾
Jimmy McGill from the commercial.
您想過來咨詢一下嗎
Would you look to come in for a consultation?
親民  親民一點
Folksy -- be folksy.
我是聽到小狗的叫聲了嗎
Say, is that a dog I'm hearing?
真的
It is?
它叫什么名字
Aww, what's her name?
餅干桶餐館
Yeah, Cracker Barrel.
提到餅干桶餐館總會有幫助
It always helps to mention Cracker Barrel.
您讓瑪格麗特在屋里玩是個好主意
Well, I think it's great you let Margaret play inside.
外面可熱了
It's a hot one out there.
我在想一會兒去餅干桶餐館呢
I was thinking of going over to Cracker Barrel
他們那兒的空調特別棒
because they've got such great air-conditioning.
他們家的餅干也不錯
Well, yes, I love their biscuits, too.
太棒了
Well, that's wonderful.
遺囑確實很重要
Yes, I think a will is really important.
您想什么時候過來和麥吉爾先生見面
When would you like to come in and meet Mr. McGill?
"吉米"  是吉米
"Jimmy"! Jimmy.
永遠都是吉米
Always Jimmy.
這周五有空
Uh, this Friday is open.
對
Yes.
吉米九點有空  這時間可以嗎
Jimmy has a 9:00 free. Will that work?
好極了
Fantastic.
能拼下您的名字嗎
Can you spell your name for me?
還有聯系電話
And a number we can reach you at?
好的  桃樂茜
Okay, Dorothy.
很期待你的到來
Look forward to seein' ya.
當然  再見
You betcha. Bye, now.
非常抱歉  感謝您的耐心等待
I am so sorry. Thank you for holding.
有什么我能幫您的嗎
How may I help you?
我可以為您做個預約
Well, I can set you up with an appointment.
吉米現在很忙  如果您想...
Jimmy is busy at the moment, but if you'd like --
聽起來您在戶外
Uh, you sound like you're outdoors.
您在陰涼處嗎
Are you staying out of the sun?
今天很熱
It's a hot one today.
抱歉  吉米現在無法接聽您的電話
I'm sorry, but Jimmy is unavailable at the moment.
如果你想留個口信  厄門紹特先生嗎
If you'd like to leave a message, Mr... Ehrmantraut?
和鮭魚同音的那個嗎
"Trout," like the fish?
我聽說餅干桶餐館里的空調很好...
Uh, I hear Cracker Barrel has excellent air--
這位客戶真的對餅干桶餐館不感興趣
This one really don't want to talk about Cracker Barrel.
好  把電話轉給我
Yeah, patch that one through.
麥吉爾先生將接聽您的電話
Mr. McGill will take your call.
你的新助理真的很煩人
Your new assistant's a real pip.
謝謝你在她上班第一天就粉碎了她的積極性
Yeah, thanks for crushing her spirit on the first day.
謝謝  先生  祝你一路順風
Thank you, sir. You drive safe.
現在只有你在接聽嗎
You the only one on this line?
是的  只有我  什么事
Yeah, only me. What's up?
你明早有時間和我吃個早餐嗎
You free for breakfast tomorrow?
好了  照我說的做
All right, this is what you're gonna do.
進去  買杯咖啡  一份吃的
You're gonna go inside, buy a cup of coffee, a meal --
隨你便  然后找個座位坐下
whatever -- and sit in a booth.
大概十到十五分鐘后
Sometime in the next 10 to 15 minutes,
一個開著綠色雪佛萊開拓者的人
a guy in an old green Chevy Blazer
會在那個停車場停車
is gonna pull into that parking lot.
他背著個背包  會進店
He'll take a knapsack, and he'll go inside.
我需要你盯著那個背包
I need you to keep an eye on the knapsack.
他對那個背包做了什么都告訴我
Let me know what he does with it.
他有沒有拿什么東西出來
Does he take anything out of it?
他有沒有和誰換包
Does he switch the bag with someone?
他有沒有從包里拿出什么留下
Does he leave something from the bag inside?
好好好  我知道了
Right, right, right. I got it.
綠色雪佛蘭開拓者  車頂是黑色的
Green Chevy Blazer, black top.
知道了  包里有什么
Yeah. What's in the bag?
是錢嗎
Is it money?
肯定是錢
It's got to be money.
毒品嗎  是毒品嗎
Drugs? Is it drugs?
是其它的嗎
Something else?
我猜是錢
Well, um, I'm guessing money.
說我猜中了
Tell me I'm right.
他隨時都會到
He is gonna be here any minute.
我要你現在就進去
Now, I need you inside.
這事兒你干不干
You gonna do the job or not?
行  我干
Fine. I'll do the job.
洛博羅炸雞
你勾起了我的好奇心
You charmed me into it.
歡迎光臨洛博羅炸雞  需要點餐嗎
Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos. May I take your order?
要份經典炸雞和一杯咖啡  不加糖不加奶
Uh, I'll have a Pollos Classic and a coffee, black.
需要加五十美分加大嗎
Would you like the Pollos bonus size for 50 cents more?
不用了  普通的就行
No. Normal.
-在這吃還是帶走  -在這吃
- Dining in or to go? - Dining in.
就這些嗎
Will that be all today?
-是的  -一共三塊一毛九
- Uh, yeah. - Your total's $3.19.
需要加份莎莎醬嗎
Do you want any extra salsa?
不  番茄醬
Uh, no. Ketchup.
你好  有什么需要
Oh, hi. What can I do for you?
您的餐好了  先生
Here you go, sir.
祝您今天愉快
Have a great day.
好  你也是
Yep. You, too.
當然  如果有的話
Oh, sure, if there's one open.
你好  歡迎光臨洛博羅炸雞
Hi. Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
-真的嗎  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
你好  歡迎光臨洛博羅炸雞
Hi. Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
可以為您點餐嗎
May I take your order?
我要三號套餐  配炸土豆  咖啡
Gimme a number three. Potatoes, coffee.
-需要加五十美分加大嗎  -不了
- Would you like the Pollos bonus size for 50 cents more? - No.
在這吃還是帶走
Dining in or to go?
-在這吃  -就這些嗎
- In. - Will that be all today?
四塊八毛九
$4.89.
好的
Yeah, no problem.
你需要加份莎莎醬嗎
Do you need any extra salsa?
好  給我一份
Yeah, gimme that.
您的餐好了  祝您今天愉快
Here you go. Have a great day.
有什么需要嗎
Can I help you?
我的手表  表扣松了
My watch, uh, clasp is loose.
掉進去了
It...falls.
我想撿起來
I tried to reach it.
很抱歉
Oh. Well, I'm sorry.
讓我來吧
Allow me.
人們都說好的手表帶和手表一樣重要
Y'know, they say a nice watch band is as important as the watch.
這就是圖便宜的下場
That's what I get for cheapin' out.
會給您找到的
We'll find it for you.
到底掉哪兒去了
Where the heck is it?
別著急
Oh, don't worry.
如果真是掉進去了  我會...
If it's in here, I'll -- Ah.
在這兒呢
There it is.
需要我為您擦干凈嗎
May I clean this for you?
我們有酒精濕巾
We have alcohol wipes.
不用了  它掉進過更臟的地方
Oh, nah, it's been in worse places.
謝謝
Thank you.
真的太謝謝你了
That was very nice of you.
小事  樂意效勞
No problem. It's my pleasure.
-還有什么需要幫忙的嗎  -沒有了
- Is there anything else I can do for you? - Uh, no.
謝謝
Thanks.
保重
You take care.
再說一遍
Tell me again.
老天  你要我用幾種不同的方式來說
Jesus. How many different ways you want me to say it?
告訴我你看到了什么
Just tell me what you saw.
就像你說的  他走進來
He came in, like you said he would.
點了套餐三  外加炸土豆和咖啡
He ordered the number three with potatoes and coffee,
還多要了莎莎醬
went bold with the extra salsa,
然后他從左前口袋掏出現金結了賬
and he paid cash out of his left front pocket.
拿著他的托盤
Uh, took his tray of food,
坐在了餐廳東邊的座位上
sat in a booth on the east side of the restaurant,
把背包放在地上
and put the knapsack on the floor.
地上哪兒
Where on the floor?
座位下方  夾在兩條腿之間
Under his seat, between his legs.
沒人碰過
Nobody touched it.
他也沒跟任何人說過話
He didn't talk to anybody.
他甚至沒正眼瞧過別人
He didn't even look at anybody.
頂多五分鐘就吃完了
Finished his meal in five minutes, tops,
然后就走了  什么都沒留下
and skedaddled -- didn't leave anything behind.
你確定嗎
And you're sure of that?
我還檢查了垃圾桶
I literally checked the trash can.
除了垃圾  里面啥都沒有
There was nothing in there but trash.
下一步我們怎么做
So...what's our next move, huh?
要跟蹤這個人嗎
Are we gonna follow this guy?
因為你有這個007特工用的東西
'Cause you -- you got some real James Bond stuff in here.
這車里不會有彈射座椅吧
This car doesn't have an ejector seat, does it?
今天就這樣吧
I think we're done for today.
-就完事了  -完事了
- That's it? - That's it.
我可是取消了早上的日程
I mean, I cleared my morning.
我們難道不...
What -- we're not gonna do, like,
尾隨他到下一個地點嗎
tail him to a new location?
我們至少得盯牢他吧...
Or, I mean, we got to sit on him, at least. I --
抱歉耽誤了你的時間
Thanks for your time.
誰是你堅實的后盾
Hey, who's got your back, huh?
就是我
Me -- that's who.
這話我會記著
I'll keep that in mind.
均為車型和顏色
目標
金  和亞利桑那州監管員的電話會議
Oh, Kim, the conference call with the Arizona regulator
得改期了
needs to be rescheduled.
周四可以嗎
Thursday okay?
好  沒問題
Oh, yeah, that's fine.
好的
Okay.
弗朗西斯卡  我們還有那種
Francesca, have we got any more
低熱量黃油曲奇餅干嗎
of those dietetic butter cookies?
我找找
I can check.
謝謝
Thanks.
歡迎各位
Welcome, folks!
歐尼  什么事
Hey, Ernie. What's up?
你不能進來嗎
Can't you just come inside?
抱歉
Sorry.
謝了
Thanks.
什么事
What are we doing out here?
我不想給你打電話
I didn't want to call you
因為這樣會留下通話記錄
because then it would leave a phone record.
我本來想進去的
I was gonna come in,
但我轉念一想  或許吉米不該見到我
but then I thought maybe Jimmy shouldn't see me.
所以...
So...
但你打給我了
But you just called me.
可能我早就搞砸了
Guess I screwed up already.
歐尼  搞砸什么
Ernie, screwed what up?
你為什么不想見吉米
Why don't you want to see Jimmy?
是因為...
Well, it's just...
我不知道怎么開頭
I'm not sure how to start.
實話跟我說就行
You can start by just telling me.
事情是這樣的
Here's the thing.
我有一些情報
I have some information,
但我不想惹上麻煩
but I don't want to get in trouble.
和吉米的麻煩
Trouble with Jimmy?
不  是哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
No. With HHM.
我受保密協議的限制  是吧
I think I'm bound by confidentiality, maybe?
我不太懂法律知識
I'm a little hazy on the legal points,
但如果我告訴你我聽到的
but if I tell you what I heard
而不是直接告訴吉米
and not Jimmy directly,
就像一個緩沖...
like... like, we have a buffer,
那從法律上說我就是安全的咯
then legally, I'm safe?
歐尼
Ernie.
你到底在說什么啊
What the hell are you talking about?
我只是擔心吉米
I'm -- I'm just worried about Jimmy.
如果我告訴他...
But if I tell him...
我也不想惹上麻煩
I don't want to get in trouble, too.
告訴吉米什么
Tell Jimmy what?
莉莉  謝謝你帶你母親過來
Lily, I want to thank you for bringing your mom down.
很高興見到您  年輕女士
It was a delight to meet you, young lady.
謝謝你  吉米
Thank you, Jimmy.
告訴您的朋友們
And you tell your friends,
就算他們已經立了遺囑
even if they already have a will,
更新也是很重要的
it's important to get it updated,
-就像您一樣  -我會告訴他們的
- just like you did. - I'll tell them.
這位是弗朗西斯卡
Now, you remember Francesca --
接下來她會幫你處理好的
she'll take care of you the rest of the way.
好了  下一個  威切爾先生
All right, who's next? Mr. Witchell.
威切爾先生  該您了
Mr. Witchell, come on down!
您是"稱心價"的下一位選手
You're the next contestant on "The Price is Right"!
吉米  可以借用幾分鐘嗎
Jimmy, can I have a moment?
-抱歉  先生  -看起來一切都...
- Excuse me, sir. - Um, looks like everything is...
抱歉  威切爾先生
Apologies, Mr. Witchell.
-我過會就回來  -天啊
- I'll just be a second, folks. - Oh, my gosh.
你們今天在餅干桶餐館喝過湯嗎
Have you guys had the soup over at Cracker Barrel today?
怎么了
What?
怎么了  快說呀
What?! Hey, come on.
還有委托人在等我
I got people out there.
-在聽嗎   我不...  -給我一美元
- Hello. I can't -- - Give me a dollar.
-給你一美元  -沒錯  給我就行
- Give you a dollar? - Yeah, just hand me a dollar.
-好吧  -快
- Okay. - C'mon.
我只有一張二十的
All I got's a $20.
好  無所謂
Fine. Whatever.
我現在是你的律師
All right. I'm your lawyer now.
如果有人問我知道什么
If anyone asks me what I know,
我們就有保密協議了
we have confidentiality.
我們為什么要保密
Why do we need confidentiality?
吉米  你跟查克說什么了
Jimmy, what did you say to Chuck?
終于來了
Here it comes.
是霍華德吧
Howard, right?
霍華德給你打電話了  別緊張
Did Howard call? R-Relax.
不  請讓我解釋
No. Let me explain, please.
拜托
Please.
金  讓我給你說明一下  好嗎
Kim, let me set the stage for you, okay?
我上周去查克家時
When I went to Chuck's place last week,
好像進了爆米花包裝袋里一樣
it was like the inside of a Jiffy Pop wrapper, all right?
墻面上都是聚酯薄膜
There was Mylar on the walls.
連天花板上都是聚酯薄膜  天花板上
There was Mylar on the ceiling -- the ceiling.
他以為他的腦子壞掉了
He thought his brain wasn't working
因為梅薩維德那件事
because of the Mesa Verde of it,
所以我跟他說
and so I kinda told him
他之前的猜想都是對的
that he was right about everything.
我必須這么做
I had to.
他  他  金  他崩潰了
He -- He -- Kim, he was broken.
他崩潰了啊
He was a broken man!
我不能讓他那樣瘋癲下去
I couldn't leave him in Crazy Town like that!
所以我跟他說了  為了讓他好受些
So I told him, you know, just to make him feel better,
但是他說什么都不要緊
but it doesn't matter what he says --
他告訴誰都沒關系
it doesn't matter who he tells,
因為空口無憑
because it's my word against his!
吉米  有錄音帶
Jimmy, there's a tape.
什么
What?
有一卷錄了你和查克對話的錄音帶
There is a tape recording of you talking to Chuck.
你什么意思  誰錄的
What do you mean? Who? Who?
他對我錄了音  怎么錄的
He -- He taped me? How?
我不知道怎么錄的
I don't know how.
他就是錄了  好嗎  歐尼告訴我的
He just did, okay? Ernie told me.
歐尼告訴你的
Ernie told you?
他說查克把一個錄音機
He said Chuck has a tape recorder
卷在太空毯里  放在他書桌的抽屜里
wrapped in a space blanket in his desk drawer.
歐尼給錄音機換新電池時
Ernie was putting new batteries in it for Chuck,
錄單帶播了幾秒
and the tape rolled for a few seconds,
他聽到你  你的聲音...
and he heard you -- your voice --
在說什么把1261改成了1216
saying something about switching 1261 to 1216.
很顯然  這是你的認罪錄音
So, clearly, it was this confession of yours.
他對我錄了音
He taped me?
是的  吉米
Yes, Jimmy.
但是我不確定他能用它干什么...
But I'm not sure what he can do with it...
反正法律上來講是這樣
...legally, anyway.
我得去研究一下
I'm gonna have to do some research.
他錄這卷帶子是有原因的
He made that tape for a reason,
我們只要找出原因就行了
and we just have to figure out why.
吉米
Jimmy?
我得回去了
I gotta get back to it.
大廳里都是委托人
The lobby's full of clients.
好的
Okay.
我們會有辦法解決的
We'll figure this out.
是的  我知道
Yeah. I know.
抱歉讓大家久等了
Sorry for the delay, everyone!
威切爾先生  感謝您的耐心
Mr. Witchell, thank you for your patience.
我看到您把文件都帶來了
I see you brought paperwork.
我得說
I got to say,
我絕對想不到可以收集瓶蓋
I would never have thought to collect bottle caps.
這是個很棒的愛好
It's a wonderful hobby.
最吸引我的就是搜尋的過程
What excites me is the hunt.
我可以想像
I can imagine.
跟您合作很愉快  蒂勒先生
Pleasure doing business with you, Mr. Tiller.
謝謝你  吉米
Why, thank you, Jimmy.
好了  您開車小心
All right, then. You drive safe.
我會的
I do.
這是最后一個了嗎
Is that the last one,
我們有落下什么人嗎
or we got any stragglers coming through?
是最后一個
Last one.
好的  謝謝  弗朗西斯卡
Well, hey, thanks, Francesca.
你今天表現非常棒
You were great today.
你也是
You, too.
這些老家伙喜歡你
Those folks love you.
誰會不喜歡我呢
Who doesn't?
是麥基弗公訴案嗎
And that's U.S. versus McKeever?
好的  不  有道理
Right. No, it makes sense.
你對我的幫助非常大  教授
You were a tremendous help, professor.
謝謝你抽出時間
Thanks for finding the time.
你也是
You, too.
再次感謝你
Thanks again.
弗朗西斯卡  能幫我個忙嗎
Francesca, could you do me a favor?
去我的辦公室  把梅薩維德文件里
Can you go through the Mesa Verde files in my office
貼有《社區再投資法案》標簽的文件拿出來
and pull all the ones labeled "CRA evaluations"
然后按時間排個序  好嗎
and sort them by date?
我要確保我有最新的文件
I need to make sure I have the most recent.
-沒問題  -謝謝你
- Absolutely. - Thank you.
-我馬上就去找你  -好的
- I'll join you in a minute. - Okay.
我剛剛給我以前的
So... just got off the phone
刑事訴訟法教授打了電話
with my old Crim-Pro professor.
是嗎  他怎么說
Oh, yeah? What'd he say?
新墨西哥州實行"一方同意"
Well, as we know, New Mexico is one-party consent,
所以查克有權錄音
so Chuck had a right to make the recording.
但你去找他是擔心他的精神狀況
But you went to him worried for his mental health.
告訴他你做過的事是為了安慰他
You said the things you did to make him feel better,
這至少會減輕你的認罪程度
which mitigates the admission of guilt, at the very least.
我們可以從監護權這方面著手
We can poke holes in the custody,
質疑錄音帶里的聲音不是你的
throw doubt the voice on the tape is even yours.
即使不成功
Even failing that,
該證據的有害影響也高過其證明價值
its probative value doesn't outweigh how prejudicial it is.
我們可以利用403法案反駁
I think we can get the whole thing bounced under 403.
也許可以將它徹底排除在證據之外
Probably get it excluded outright.
那么...
So, then...
法庭之外  又能做什么呢
outside the courts, what can you do?
放給梅薩維德的凱文聽嗎
Play the tape for Kevin at Mesa Verde?
他到目前為止都還沒有
He hasn't up to now.
否則我肯定聽到風聲
I'd have heard something, for sure.
而且我認為他不會那樣做
And you know what? I don't think he's going to.
霍華德不會任由他把那盤帶子送到梅薩維德
I don't think Howard will let him near Mesa Verde with that tape.
他知道那會有損律所的形象
Howard knows it would make HHM look terrible.
如果查克對那盤帶子有所計劃
If Chuck has a plan for this tape,
我猜不到會是什么
I don't know what it is.
現在  我們只能等他先出招
At this point, all we can do is wait for his move,
再采取相應的行動
then act accordingly.
那好吧
All right, then.
謝謝
Thanks.
不客氣
Sure.
對了  你覺得怎么樣
Oh, hey, what do you think?
這是"藍色練習曲"搭配"白日夢收獲"
It's "Etude in Blue" over "Daydream Harvest."
我希望看起來像桑迪亞斯的清晨
I wanted it to look like morning over the Sandias.
我喜歡  很漂亮
I like it. It looks nice.
看起來不會像股市崩盤嗎
It doesn't look like a stock-market crash?
不會  一點都不像
No. It doesn't look like a stock-market crash.
很漂亮
It's nice.
謝謝
Thanks.
你還好吧
You okay?
金  我沒事
Kim, I'm good.
喂
Yeah.
霍華德  你來這里干什么
Howard, what are you doing here?
-查克  你有空嗎  -你有沒有...
- Chuck, do you have a second? - Did you --
你有沒有把車停到隔壁街
You parked over on the next block?
有  停得很遠
Oh, yeah. Way over.
手機  鑰匙
Phone. Keys.
你得把它們藏起來
You have to hide them.
沒事吧  先生
Everything okay, sir?
沒事  謝謝  大衛  你先下去吧
Yes, thank you, David. Give us a moment.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
-怎么了  -查克
- What's up? - Chuck...
這事已經過了八天了
this has been going on for eight days now,
確實沒有任何跡象表明能成功
and really, no indication that it's going to work.
會成功的
It will work.
我自認很有耐心了
I think I've been very patient,
可是
but the cost of these
請這些全天候私家偵探的費用
'round-the-clock private investigators is...
真的非常高昂
really starting to add up.
霍華德  這是我們的職責
Howard, this is our duty.
身為律師
As officers of the court,
我們有義務去...
we have an ethical obligation to --
-沒錯  -我弟弟觸犯了法律
- Yes. - My brother broke the law.
我們不能袖手旁觀
We can't just sit back and do nothing.
我不是要你什么都不做
I'm not talking about doing nothing.
我只是想...  思路放寬點
I just want to... free up our minds
對其他策略保持開放態度
and be open to alternate strategies, please.
我們各讓一步吧
Meet me halfway here.
我們  我們可以只在夜間
I suppose -- I suppose we could limit the investigators
聘請私家偵探
to just nighttime hours.
-夜間  -是的
- Nighttime. - Yes.
吉米很可能趁我睡覺時
Jimmy will most likely break in
偷偷闖進來
while he thinks I'm sleeping --
他什么都做得出來
I mean, I wouldn't put anything past him.
只是最合理的猜測是
It just makes the most sense
他會趁著天黑進來偷帶子
he'll try to steal the tape under cover of darkness.
你真的認為他會那樣做
You really think he's going to do that?
是的
I do, indeed.
你怎么能如此肯定呢
How can you be so sure?
霍華德  我很了解我的弟弟
Howard, I know my brother.
查克
Chuck!
快開門  查克
Open the damn door, Chuck!
快開門啊
Open the door, damn it!
-開門  查克  -吉米  你走吧
- Open it! Chuck! - Jimmy, go away!
開門啊
Open the door!
-給我開門  -我不會開門的
- Open it now! - I'm not opening the door!
-我發誓  查克  -我不會開...  吉米
- I swear to God, Chuck... - I am not op-- Jimmy!
-吉米  -你居然把我的話錄下來  混蛋
- Jimmy! - You taped me?! You asshole!
吉米
Jimmy!
你假裝跟我掏心掏肺
You pulled that heartstrings con job on me?!
你個人渣
You piece of shit!
"我的頭腦曾經那么敏捷
"My brain used to work.
我病了  我不知道如何是好"
I'm sick. I don't know what to do!"
混蛋
Asshole!
難怪麗貝卡離開你了
No wonder Rebecca left you!
她怎么能忍你那么久
What took her so long?!
找到了
There it is!
來吧
Here we go.
Here we go!
來吧
就是這個嗎
Is this it?
你就為了這個  毀了我們的家
For this, you destroyed our family?
你現在滿意了嗎
You happy now?!
為了什么  根本毫無意義
For what?! For nothing!
就只有這一盤嗎  查克
Is that all there is, Chuck?
只有這一盤嗎
It's all the -- all there is?
還是你有其他拷貝  有嗎  查克
Or'd you make copies? Huh, Chuck? Huh?
你告訴我
You tell me,
不然我就把這棟破房子燒個精光
or I'll burn this whole goddamn house to the ground!
吉米  吉米
Jimmy! Jimmy!
夠了
That's enough!
你離他遠點
You need to step away.
霍華德
Howard...
你目擊了剛剛發生的事嗎
you were a witness to what happened here?
是的
I was.
你呢
And you?
我也看到了
I'm a witness.